Hank good morning sleep well no garbage
trucks making noise outside let's start
with the meditation okay Buddha said
first stage step of meditation
turn off his cell phone gemios $50 to
die Mountain you all $50 to Diamond
Mountain America not singapore just
kidding just kidding blow your nose
we're going to go through the
preliminaries for meditation it's the
same as preliminaries in the three
treasures book and if you don't have a
three treasures but can somebody hold up
a three treasures but you know if you
don't have one you should get one today
this morning they're in the book store I
think okay you need one
you can't meditate without one okay okay
let's go
so many people ask me about the pleasure
island shemitah they want to know the
secret secrets of meditation and these
preliminary practices the things you do
this before you start meditating are a
big secret to shemitah I think
meditation because you can't meditate if
you're if you have some negative things
in your mind from the last few weeks and
you can't meditate without your heart
teachers help whoever your heart teacher
is so this is part of schemata big part
so relax your eyelids pulling your
stomach light slightly and keep it
slightly tense small smile on your face
don't get too serious relax your fingers
and relax your shoulders the muscles of
your shoulders watch your forehead don't
let it get tight watch your eyelids make
sure they're relaxed and then slow they
come to your breath today let's just do
long exhale let's not try to count to
ten just see if you can focus on nice
long slow exhale
you
and please invite your art teacher to
come and sit with you could be a
historical teacher like Jesus or Buddha
mama
it could be someone you haven't met yet
some ideal teacher in your future could
be someone who's alive now but whoever
you feel close to could be your parents
just an inspiring friend
try to capture the feeling of sitting
with someone that you very much admire
and love try to capture the feeling of
affection rather than a picturing
then we bow down to them in our mind by
thinking of some beautiful quality one
of the many beautiful qualities that
someone we have chosen as a teacher must
have focus on one
then negative an offering could a
beautiful flower that you imagined
beautiful sunset beautiful sky best
offering is your practice even master
commercial I talked about our Buddha
offered his practice tears Lamas for
over two hundred thousand lifetimes
recently so think of some small success
you're having attempts you're making an
operative to your teachers
then open your heart try to feel like
you're opening your chastised in the way
that you'd unbutton your shirt so your
unbuttoning your Chester bearing your
heart showing your heart and your mama
and talking honestly about your bad
habits fault
to help make them clean
this will really help your stomach turn
and then today we'll choose something
good we've seen somebody else do there
are lots of good examples in dynamo
people working very very hard to serve
us help us dedicating their whole year
so that we can have good retreats here
and just share with your Lama a few
examples you've seen of people who
sacrificed their own lives what they
would like to do in they're working
really hard here to keep it ready for us
to do retreat
and ask your mama to teach you all the
teachings that come to us during the day
happy ones Dharma teachings Dharma books
and difficult teachings like a good
friend correcting us or even someone
criticizing us they all come from our
teacher ultimately soon after teacher to
keep teaching is whether they are easy
inspired teachings or whether they're
difficult teaching study improve us
then ask your llama to stay close tenure
stay in your life we must have done
something good in the past to have
someone who's interested in us wants to
help us ask them to keep trying even
even if we're very stubborn sometimes
then ask your teacher to stay in your
heart and they slowly start to rise up
off the ground still facing you and that
they rise up to the level of your chest
then the level of your face they start
to get smaller and when they rise above
your hand they turn and face the same
way yes you and then they come down
softly on the top of your head maybe a
few inches high 3 4 inches high you can
feel the soft pressure of a small
teacher pressing on the top of your head
then invite them into your heart and
they shrink smaller size of your thumb
then this size of a pea and they mount
into the top of your head and they start
to come down in front of your spine
through your central channel you can
feel their progress does central channel
through your skull to your neck tune
throat and into your chest and then they
keep shrinking it's much easier to hold
your focus in meditation if you shrink
the object to something tiny
so shrink it to the size of a grain of
sugar put them in the very center of
your heart almost like they're sitting
in a glob of crystals and they're very
relaxed and happy themselves always
happy but also very happy that you are
meditating you're trying your best and
they agree to stay there all day all
night constantly influencing us for
better constant inspiring and good
influence on us
then thank them and come to your breath
again three long exhales you can think
that each exhale is sending anonymous
blessings out to the world and the good
color of your practice making a peaceful
world happy world and you can slowly
open your eyes take a stretch
people always asking me the secret to
Vipassana and the secret to shamaton
that's a big one okay
then they said well you taught that
already and I said yeah but you didn't
do it every day okay first thing in the
morning especially on retreat okay
that's that's a big secret they say the
best way to hide something is put it out
on a table where everybody can see it
okay so do we have a printout yet of the
can we pass them out or are they secret
okay that's not okay good
my first couple Chinese
all right can I have her
it's okay that's okay that's okay that's
okay I am all right
by the way meditation number 20 from
last time the guys you know he plunged
he's pushing a plunger which is what
sends the electricity to blow up the
dynamite you've seen it in all the
movies there really is a thing like that
and you have to imagine that meditations
about that that gap between the cause
and the effect
okay when does the circuit closed you
know how many atoms have to touch before
the electricity can pass and what's the
edge of the atom look like how can two
things touch okay and yes just a picture
has meaning okay and I've told you
before but I'll tell you again if you
can memorize the pictures you will
remember the meditations okay and then
you don't have to use a paper okay so
that's what the photos are for it takes
a long time to find them and the first
pictures of you teaching diamond cutter
to somebody okay third picture is what
you can talk in the class to me what's
the third one
what's it the stream enter okay someone
entering the stream it's called the
first of the four fruits
in Buddhism we talk about the four
fruits or four results of your practice
the first one is called entering the
stream and we didn't quite finish it
yesterday because it got late okay and
by the way I you know being here I was
sitting thinking about whether I can
finish , co3 so I decided to finish it
so I'll just keep I split it up and
we'll cover a certain amount every day
and it might take more than what the
schedule says okay but that way we just
finish it okay
all right okay so all right here we go
master Carla Sheila about meditation 21
meditation 21 from last time level
hemisphere to is about how does a person
who's seeing emptiness how does an eye
directly how does an ayah feel about
what they did you see because if they
thought that their study and practice
and meditation caused it right in a way
that touched it you think like the
dynamite thing it's connected to the
dynamite plunger does your effort create
spiritual results it's a really nice
bunny running around outside and then
you have to understand you know the
nature efforts that you make and then
spiritual results that you get okay
and even when you reach a place where
you understand that things are coming
from the seed you planted by being nice
to other people right
you have to understand that getting to
that place also as a result of being
nice to other people okay so when you
get to a place because you've been
understanding seeds don't forget that
that place also comes from seeds or
you'll be kicked out of that place okay
got it
then master camera Sheila divides a
sentence into three parts the sentences
now I have reached the goal of entering
the stream now I have seen emptiness
okay he takes that one sentence and he
divides it into three parts okay
and he says now I when you say now I
would stream enter who's I who's me okay
and maybe at that moment you forget you
yourself your body your own thoughts are
popping out of comma seeds that you
planted last week okay so when you say I
did it I reached the goal then you have
to remember if you don't remember
Michael is coming out of the seeds that
he planted last week or two weeks ago if
you don't remember that you get kicked
out of your understanding okay
the minute you say I did I get booked
you kick out is there an i yes is there
Michael yes okay why didn't we have a
good idea called I you know why cuz he
shared diamond cutter sit there with
other people which connects to the first
picture we had so everything connects
okay got it thank goodness I was trying
to help Rosa
last week understand diamond cutter
because now I saw emptiness you know
that's I okay I have obtained is
dangerous the verb of the
sentence I attained okay I did but
there's no dead either okay it just
seems opening okay even in your own mind
you are the listener you are listening
to thoughts that are coming out of seeds
that you planted last week if you were
talking mean about somebody else last
week then when those seeds altering your
mind your your own mind feels depressed
okay people ask me can you use Buddhism
to treat depression I say no it's too
late this leads open my lama is to say
you can't push it through back in the
ground there's a really nice a street
here how long has it been here mountain
air I want more I mean don't get me one
I'm just say I'm gonna guess it's doing
pretty well twelve years oh that's too
long I want to grow a tree fast enough
to have a a tree house to meditate it
but we haven't found a truly art we're
working on it
anyway when you hear thoughts in your
mind of depression it's because you you
made someone else sad a week ago or a
month ago in a little way and those
seeds grew they doubled every day and
now you have to listen to them okay you
can stop
next week seeds by being encouraging to
other people this week but once the
seeds are opening and the words are
coming out and you're listening to them
in your mind you can't stop them at that
point that's like trying to stop a tree
that you watered and you put the seed
and the fertilizer and it's too late
you should stop planting trees if you
don't like them okay then you could stop
it for listening okay so I reached I
reached a direct assumption emptiness be
careful about the reached the verb
that's another chance for your mind to
think that's coming from its own side
okay it's another chance to make a
mistake and when you make that mistake
the idea become law Sheila and the idea
in the diamond cutter Sutra is you get
kicked out of it you get pushed out of
seeing emptiness because you said I
reached okay is it wrong to say in these
no but just understand that every time
you have a spiritual breakthrough it's
because you help somebody else have a
spiritual breakthrough okay okay
obviously that would reduce your pride
right okay it's not really you okay okay
and then the last chance in the sentence
to make a mistake is with the object of
the verb I reached the Gulf the Gulf
I saw emptiness you know the goal I
reached a direct perception of emptiness
okay then that's a third chance to get
kicked out of this you're under your
level of understanding because you think
the ball is coming from its own side and
it's not okay that's also created
specifically by sharing your
understanding of emptiness with other
people and there's this famous famous
DCI question geshe-la
how can I help other people make money
if I want money if I don't know how to
make money that's why I don't have money
some huh y-you want me to how can i DS
emptiness to other people so I can see
emptiness because that means I don't
understand it when I'm teaching and
Buddha said ready as much as you
understand okay that's okay you
understand 5% teach 5% be honest with
other people you know don't say I saw
emptiness ten years ago and I'm sharing
it with you you can see I went to many
classes on emptiness I slept through
most of them but I understood like five
percent and I'm gonna share with you and
then that's the cost to reach that goal
okay got it so in this picture what's
the picture quick yeah it's a lady on
the river offering to get you into the
stream she's already in the stream right
she's trying to share what she
understands as much as she the five
percent that she understands come to the
river with me you know let try to see
emptiness okay
all right he goes into some logic about
all this it's kind of difficult my it's
like taking out the garbage I took out
the garbage this morning it's kind of
difficult it's stinky and you know it's
more fun to have coffee than to take out
the garbage and sometimes when you're
reading a book like common-law Cielo and
you get to a hard part you want to just
skip it like taking out the garbage you
know then I try to slow down you know I
try to stop and tell myself you can't
have dessert until you finish your
vegetables
you know okay so here it is he's talking
about the Gulf and he's talking about
why it's not self-existent okay so I
read the Gulf
so Gulf he says it's either producing or
an unproduced thing okay almost
everything in our world is produced by
causes okay
almost everything almost everything we
come in contact with all day is produced
by causes there's a few things that are
not like three okay
I'll be dumbest history Democrat Bernie
go bunny space is one of them you you
guys most many of you learn the four
spaces meditations and that idea that
you are sitting in a place in a space
even if this planet was blown up into
dust and it went away and you're you
were evaporated by some bomb or
something still the place that you are
occupying with would be there
it's unchanging and no one made it it's
always been there and it will always be
there okay so he says what do you think
is the goal of seeing emptiness toric
lee is it a producing or unproduced
thing it's produced I mean like by
studying carla Sheila it's the goal is
produced right the object of the goal is
not produced right emptiness is not
produced it's the absence of the second
husband okay
the husband who yelled at you who's not
your fault okay we talked about it in
the lamrim class okay all day long
there's two husbands in your kitchen one
is coming from what you did last week
one is not that's not my father I didn't
do anything okay you can take a deep
breath because it's that one long word
it's not much far I didn't do anything
he's yelling at me but I don't know why
I just came home I just opened the door
you know that husband who's not your
phone it's never there was never there
will never be there cannot be there no
okay the fact that it's not there is
emptiness all gasp Allah that's not
mythical enough sorry
the goal of emptiness is to is to stop
your anger for example and that will
stop your anger immediately if you
understand this irritating husband came
from you then the only person you can
blame is someone it's you all right and
then you can't get angry I mean maybe
you can get upset at yourself but you
can't get angry and the other person
didn't do anything it's not that you
didn't do anything they didn't do
anything okay all right so if the goal
of seeing emptiness directly is is it
it's a now I'm going back to commercial
if she said if it was a produced thing
it has to fit what Buddha said all
through the Sutra which is K me kill'em
a government in the words in the garner
which we're going to do next year
nothing starts and nothing stops okay so
if the Buddha was correct then the goal
entering the stream seeing emptiness
directly never started so can it be a
produced thing no it never started
produced means somebody put the seed and
the fertilizer in the water and the tree
came out okay
the goal but it's not Britta said
nothing starts okay that's seed the
water the fertilizer of the mountain ash
out there never touched the tree the
tree was the seed was gone by the time
the tree groove the seed never touched
the tree okay
garden it's not coming the way you think
yeah nothing to do therefore the goal
cannot be what you thought it was got it
all right
it goes back to he says saying the goal
came from the seed of your efforts is
like a rabbit horn okay it means that
rabbits don't have horns you can check
these bunnies running around outside and
they don't grow horns so it's an old
example for something that can't exist
okay reaching the goal cannot exist
that's why you have to try to reach it
okay
[Music]
is it some kind of hippie thing where
you go into the void and you don't try
to think about nothing I've met people
who tried to do that for you know years
and I told you in DC I you can tell them
you need to turn up the volume of the
Teresa but they those people who think
that's emptiness they become forgetful
they can't find their keys they lose
their cell phones they walk around like
this you ask them to do something for
them on in there
you know you fire them okay they're not
functional if you really understand
emptiness you should be super functional
you see you should get things done
easily and be happy and engaged and
intelligent and inspired okay not the
opposite okay Stanley
yeah I know
even the law of karma and conditioner
even the Lord of karma like if you do
good you get good it's empty they're
coming from you they're not the way you
think so you mean they could be the
other way like you do crazy things and
you get good results and you asked us to
think about it today what's the Karma
you did to create that consistency right
can I say they are the fact that if you
do good you get good it's like a fact
it's am unproduced
it belong to your fewer unchanging facts
are unproduced that's true so that it's
truth are introduced so that's why they
are consistent and not exactly there's
changing unconcern there's changing
things which are consistent no changing
things okay long story are basically
what I wanted you to say was being
consistent in how you behave with other
people you know being consistently kind
consistently on time or consistently
considerate creates consistency in your
life called Karma the lots of color
okay so so it's possible that there's a
world that don't have this consistency
yeah
[Laughter]
I know but that inconsistency was
created by a consistent result
consistent cost okay all right now I'm
going to have this debate from Earl and
other people okay okay hmm now you know
I could stop giving you all these
details but I I'm gonna do it anyway
may we go talk noon I don't care do we
have juices today yeah yeah thank you
I I didn't remind you and I was placing
bets in my mind if I didn't remind
you're firing didn't okay if someone
didn't understand all these points then
they would get kicked out of being a
stream enter if they said I reached
stream enter and didn't understand what
was what happened there would be kicked
out a stream enter we said that several
times then Karla Sheila says it's worse
than that if a person who saw emptiness
directly said I saw Antonis directly and
misunderstood the I saw and the Antonis
if they misunderstood those three that
would be the truth of suffering they
would be creating new suffering for
themselves forget they get kicked out of
are you okay is the truth of the past is
the truth of the end of suffering there
are four truths and Buddhism right but
if a bodhisattva misunderstood the level
they reached it's not only not the level
anymore
it's new suffering it's new causes for
suffering okay any time you
misunderstand anything you are creating
new causes
suffering they got kicked out of the
truth of the path they got kicked out of
the truth of the end of sufferings and
they got kicked into knew suffering okay
every time you misunderstand anything
you create more trouble for yourself
okay so come but she was like British
being nice but all British said was you
get kicked out of your Aria but he says
it's worse than that you're creating new
suffering new link number 1 in the Wheel
of Life
okay alright just we won't get anywhere
it's up to you don't don't complain that
I went on too long I'm sorry do you mean
well the stream inter is seeing
emptiness to have the solder after the
automatic meditation it would have to be
after but even if they start thinking
about themselves in a correct way
during they would still get kicked out
of the director says okay your self is
not ultimate reality I didn't know it'd
be possible to for them to have that
thought after they saw I'm jeanna
because they've it's not really good as
just being exaggerating okay thank you
he wants us to understand how tricky
things are okay all right
remember that master kamila Sheila tries
to connect each part to one of the
booties three questions which one do you
think he's talking about in this section
remember there's three questions how
should we live how should we practice
how should we think
yes how should we think because that's
all about Yonghwa don't get destructive
don't let your mind get distracted in
meditation practice getting distracted
means thinking about lunch when you're
trying to think about your Lama and I
always make a joke you know
sometimes in my meditation this
beautiful Lamas face become a big
sandwich
slowly I mean I I don't notice it until
after the sandwich came out then there's
a nice beautiful body and a mac and
there's a sandwich on top and I'm like
oops I got distracted in meditation
that's not what we're talking about here
what are we talking about here
you you're really good on understanding
your husband's coming from you you come
home you are tired when you're tired you
make mistakes okay you just came home
from work you're tired when you're tired
you make mistakes you come in your
husband says something unkind here and
because you're tired you forget your
understanding of emptiness and you say
why did okay ready one deep breath I
didn't do anything I didn't do anything
why is he yelling at me okay then you
get angry okay by the way we're going to
have that flow chart later kumla Sheila
gives the whole flow chart okay what
goes on in those seconds when your
husband yells at you okay
how you get hurt okay so this section of
the suture relates to the third question
don't get distracted meaning don't
forget he's coming from you it doesn't
mean thinking about hamburger in your
China meditate on any lumber okay then
Buddha goes through the other three
fruits of Dharma practice they're called
the four fruits of Dharma practice team
mentor is the first one what's the
second one
yeah once returner means you come back
to the desire realm one more time okay
you you you saw emptiness it helps you
overcome your bad habits and you're
almost clean but not quite so you have
to come back to this realm one more time
this is the class for the students who
are work were students this planet
called Earth is the place where they put
were students the better students
already went to other places you okay
so it means that you flunk you can't go
on to the next class you have to stay
here one more time okay like first grade
or second grade they say ok you
everybody else can't go to third grade
but you have to stay in 2nd grade ok
then what's the third root of virtuous
practice non returner don't have to come
back to this realm okay you get to go to
third grade but you're still in
elementary school which is like a
terrible place ok you said go to forum
realm formless room you don't have to
come back to this place this place is
miserable nothing goes right here what's
the fourth result uh-huh you don't have
to come back you you don't have to you
and never again are you forced to come
back to this world ok you can come back
if you want to help people but you don't
have to your comment negative emotions
aren't forcing you back here yes
question
who have to return or have become have
haven't become are hot do they remember
what they ate the direct perception of
good question when you see emptiness
directly on that day you see your future
lies and you see this beautiful thing
that you see a death also you see I will
die in this world and I will come back
to this world and you know a kid whose
one year old came out of Mom's they
don't remember okay but they have a box
on they have a seed karmic seed okay and
then they always get bucked up Suribachi
etc means I don't know when they're like
sixteen or something they they have
another experience from their past
experiences and then part of the
powerful karma of seeing emptiness
directly is that in future lies you will
always be born into an environment of
artists there will be people around you
who always talking about emptiness they
only interested in emptiness you'll be
born into that place in the desire realm
of people who understand emptiness
they're always talking about emptiness
so you'll be brought up by people who
who do it all the time and then they
will then at some point your seeds
register it's called reassert themselves
bartók zipper okay no questions
questions later we won't finish you know
you guys will be mad at me later okay
Camila Sheila goes into the meaning of
the word our haunt I taught you it
already
our Sanskrit root our
means to be worthy to deserve something
okay odd hunt is a present participle
deserving you are worthy okay
he explains it that way re in Sanskrit
also means enemy arty and hun means to
kill or to hit somebody and in some
words it changes to him like him like a
hint sir
no killing the English word gun comes
from him okay the root hunt okay so so
the Tibetans translated our heart as
enemy destroyer our arty hug and
sometimes in a scripture like this one
you'll see the teacher explained our
hunt as someone who is worthy so you can
do it either way where you split the
word you can explain it either way okay
worthy of what the whole world make
offerings to them okay and try to
remember that whatever word you choose
enemy destroyer or a worthy one
deserving either one is just a name and
a conception placed on parts by you okay
hmm which brings up an interesting point
he goes deeper okay and I'm gonna go
with him okay I'm I don't care how long
it takes we'll take two juice breaks I
don't care the second one you can drink
water okay
he goes to a very interesting question
you see some people become an are not
worthy of offerings and respect
and the whole world respects them okay
you know they become our heart deserving
of his thanks and the whole world
respects them and sees them as an asset
okay Wow he's our heart I love you you
are so special please teach me okay
then some our hearts are born into a
place where people hate them
okay I don't know like Jesus or several
people tried to kill Buddha during his
life we talked about it in China and I
told you some of the stories I didn't
tell you all the stories because they
are very depressing but some people they
reach a high spiritual place and then
people just criticize them or they even
try to kill them okay then come by
Sheila says whose fault is that okay so
he divides our hearts into two kinds one
of them people are recognized and they
all are hot you are so cool you know and
the other kind people hate them and
crucify them or you know criticize them
okay
it's the emptiness of an are hot right
some people will see them as holy and
some people will see them as threatening
okay but whose fault is it it's the
other so Buddha's like don't forget even
done even our hands if the artist
criticized crucified etc in our belief
it's because they were hurting people in
the past and and and I believe the main
karma which is a very common Karma for
people who reach that stage is that they
were judging other people maybe not
verbally but mentally they were going
around the world and stop it Circle K on
the way from Tucson and everybody in the
circle K they're like this person's
stupid this person's just a lazy person
this person looks kind of fat you know
they're judging judging judging and then
when they reach our hunt people judge
them so he says let's try to be the
second kind of a hunt when we get to our
haunts
let's try to be the kind that's admired
by everybody and you can start working
on that now when you go home to China
and you go to Tucson Airport you have to
stop to go peepee halfway which is where
I did my three-year retreat don't judge
the people in the store okay try to be
open-minded it's a good exercise to say
there's one person in this store not me
who's a Buddha which one is it the fat
one or the lazy one or the old one you
know and then you create this karma that
when you become an are hard people will
our people will respect you and honor
you instead of criticizing you okay all
right and by the way the next part in
the Sutra the Buddha says by the you
know I'm not like bragging but I am in
our heart okay
so Buddha says yeah yeah Buddha that's
all true you know how do you know I'm
not hot okay then master kama Sheila's
like why would Cebu tea admit he's in
our hands
usually when you reach aria for example
we don't talk about it we don't tell
people where are you why they won't
believe you when they don't believe you
they make super bad karma it's one of
the worst Karma's a person can make okay
so you're actually hurting people I'm an
aria I don't believe you boom they just
got really bad karma okay so our arias
don't talk about it it's very rare for
an aria to say I'm an aria
so why do you think the booty here he
doesn't just say I'm an aria right he
says I'm bigger than an aria I'm an are
hot in the middle of the diamond cutter
Sutra he's not even supposed to be
talking he's the student the old goodest
system of teaching students never talk I
like him then somebody says Oh Buddha by
the way I'm in why do you think I think
about what's the last thing we talked I
mean what's this section yeah good he's
he's saying it's okay to say you saw him
ten years if you understand where it's
coming from then you if you don't
understand and you say sorry I'm too
nice you get kicked out of Aria if you
do understand what happened you can say
it I'm a nun hunt okay got it next
correct okay it's okay to say I'm in our
hunt you don't get kicked out of our
heart by saying I'm in our hunt you get
kicked out of our heart by saying I'm in
our hunt and not understand where it
comes from
got it so Sabrina is trying to give an
example that it's okay to say you
reached a certain stage if you
understand what you're saying okay it's
not wrong to talk about it it's wrong to
talk about it and think it came from
someplace other than your scene
okay that's all okay and then somebody
says by the way if I set out within our
heart and I didn't understand what it is
I couldn't even be an ion okay he says
it that way he says I would get kicked
out of forget getting kicked out of our
heart I would get kicked out of our you
got it okay
and those of you who are learning other
British schools like word and in the
transient of course in is commentary
here master Kamla Sheela is making a
distinction that our hearts some of the
our huts in the future even like Cebu
tea may not have seen the emptiness of
things they only saw the emptiness of
themselves they saw the emptiness of
person which is the first one you always
see Vivian's first direct experience of
emptiness will be the emptiness of
Vivier and then kamila Sheila's are
saying they can see the emptiness of
themselves but not a thing which we
first oftentimes to their part okay even
for our heart but but that puts master
kamila Sheila in the lower middle way
school okay and we'll study at some
other day that puts him in the lower
middle way school and his teacher was
shunted archita which is lower middle
high school okay why what's that mean
why should I care he's lower middle high
school what's the main idea of the lower
middle way school from the six kinds of
emptiness yeah okay my mind puts the
parts of the car together my mind puts
the parts of the pen together if I
shared pens in the past with other
people I have a seed in my mind when
that seed opens pens come out pictures
of pens come on and when I look at this
part okay two parts because I shared my
things with other people in the past I
see pen okay and a dog didn't share they
shared two toys in the process okay
they're mine their seat opens in their
mind pen doesn't come out picture of joy
comes out okay got it because they
shared Jim toys in the past now
lower-middle a school lower middle way
school but where did the two parts come
from okay I understand my mind puts them
together I understand but the two parts
were there before okay that's lower
middle way school the two parts were
already there then my mind put them
together into pen under the influence of
a seed that I planted last week by
sharing my stuff with other people got
it
lower middle way but the parts are there
and in my mind puts a picture on them
okay got it
what were the higher middle way say
parts also come from you the moment
before and there's there's nothing out
there okay every can come from you okay
they go higher okay but so he's kind of
in the lower middle way why would he be
in the lower middle way why are we
studying lower mentally
how are we think that way and also yeah
we created the book but in his time
which is also the time of chuan Tong
lower-middle way was very popular and
and his students were probably
lower-middle way so he had to teach that
way okay all right you want to go deeper
i don't care let's do it
we're just planning a nice dinner right
we have time I promise there no dinner
last thing about that in the database
okay so when I prepare for these classes
I can check a million pages I can check
most of the best books written in the
last two thousand years
okay because of the kindness of John
Brady thank you and
[Applause]
so just for your interest there's a
debate somebody said well didn't come
lishchyna know about nagamma and they
say yeah he knew about the garner so
didn't he study the sutra called
sun the near montana means written by
who
the buddha okay what what's the name of
the book it's called what I really meant
okay well and and one of the most famous
commentaries did that was written by
when you enter you enter student of
master shinsen
so we're going to translate that
beautiful commentary so somebody said
did is it like he didn't understand that
suture okay
and somebody said no no he understood it
it's the gardener's idea about the
sutras Krang okay the gardener was
correct master Kamla Sheila said we
should understand the three turnings of
the wheel according to the gardener and
the gardener said the two parts are out
there before you have the picture on it
garden ready I'll say it again Carmela
Sheila said people said you don't follow
the graduates of course I saw in the
gardener then they say what I'm the
gardener teach he said the two pieces
are out there before by themselves and
then it makes you come out of in mind
did he use the gardener to understand
the Buddha's teaching yes but he used it
the wrong way
got it I just he misunderstood the
gardener also he says I support the
gardener the guy that said the pieces
are out there already
okay got it did he follow the gardener
maybe he followed the words but not the
meaning okay got it
okay all right we finished one
meditation I'm gonna go by the way I
cancelled a lot of the meditations from
class two I had 45 or 47 I made them
into like 20-something if you want a new
class to manual you can talk to me a
course um okay it was too many okay I'm
going to do one more then we'll take a
break okay juice break what's the next
photo yeah somebody writing notice the
pages empty okay and the meditation is
called how did our Buddha receive his
teachings okay so our Buddha taught
diamond cutter food our Buddha taught
heart sutra our Buddha taught all these
sutures right after he became Buddha but
what did he study okay and how did he
get Dharma teachings like million years
ago okay and what's the answer a proof
of gratitude what's that mean anyone
want to guess yeah nice okay he got
Dharma teachings to become Buddha in his
time only because he pay respect to
other Buddha's and he thanked him he
says thank you okay the cars to get
Dharma teachings is just say thank you
okay
to the teacher okay that's all gratitude
I'm thanks for teaching that diamond
cutter Sutra okay so I
buna is a Buddha that's proof he got Dom
entities his Buddha it's proof he got
Dharma teaching if he got Dharma
teachings that's proof he thanked his
teachers a lot how many times ready
there classically we say there are three
thank you periods in an enlightened
beings life okay there are three thank
you periods in an enlightened beings
life okay before they became Buddha
there were three periods of thank you
thank you thank you to their teachers to
their Namas to to their Buddha okay in
their world okay
three trips during the first period they
think and serve 75 thousand Buddha's
okay that's called beginner okay the
second period they serve and thank
76-thousand breath
so we already got 150 1000 so far total
of 150 1000 Brina third period they
thanked seventy seven thousand more okay
so it's 75 76 77 okay
how many is that total is it to to rate
so somebody added up you okay - to rate
the human computer since tutorial so to
get a suitor like the diamond color
sutra in your world okay you have to you
must have thanked and served two hundred
and twenty eight thousand buddhas in
228,000 past lives to be here today
cool
okay and and he's talking about our buna
must have done it to other Buddha's okay
then in the diamond cutter Sutra they
start talking about that and I'll give
you their quotation from the diamond
cutter okay ready
Buddha's said to sorry Cebu T so buddy
what do you think did I receive any
teachings from a Buddha you know did I
receive teachings for example from a
Buddha called deep Ankara diphthong kata
means who makes like the Buddha who
makes life okay did I receive teachings
and and the Buddha says no because there
was no teaching that you received when
you received your teaching got it that's
why the picture has a blank page who
made the diamond cutter Sutra you did
you wrote it okay next time you have to
give a resume to get a job you could say
by the way I wrote the diamond cutting
Sutra what would the Karma that allowed
you to write the diamond cutter Sutra I
was thanking my teachers my parents my
school teachers my friends uncanny
people who hurt me I'm saying everybody
sorry and that's how I wrote the diamond
cutter Sutra okay
that's why it appeared in my world okay
it came out of the seeds of being
thankful even the people who hurt you
because they they probably do more to
develop you than the people who are
nicer right in my case I know that's
true okay got it
all right that one was pretty painless
let's see if I can make it more
complicated
Camila Sheila says one of the main
causes of understanding emptiness is to
thank other people be grateful to other
people
okay any-any the last thing he says okay
this is an easy one just by the way if
you get inspired by this section and you
say I want to thank more people in my
life be careful that you don't think
those people are not coming from you
okay so you should probably thank
yourself at home and then go thank them
okay don't forget that the people who
are nice to you and help you this
retreat center you created Michael Doug
okay you created this guy who wants to
stay on here and take care of their two
cents okay
you're created done so thank him but but
be careful at the same time to thank
yourself okay don't forget where he's
coming from okay otherwise the thanking
gets messed up okay it's infected by
self-existence okay got it
all right how long we been going to ours
women going on our half maybe it's
pee-pee time okay how long should we
take what kind of break
he was a geek everyday at Manoa he said
ten minutes they need 15 it's America
let's take a 15-minute first looks at so
gray looks at Sony first looks awesome
day Nick no prepare and empty space for
the juice okay alright let's do a
mandala Harold you're gonna do once you
got this bundle up here
okay let's start when you interrupt a
long teaching you can just when you come
back you can just do a mandala justice a
chip cookie okay and you're ready just
been up against a ganger a shame
in arming to engage embody sungazing
good day don't calm down
she launched a passion you know and
Donna country and
[Music]
alright next section of Master Camilla
Sheila's commentary of the 18 points I
think it's number 7 and it's called the
dream to create your own Buddha paradise
ok the dream to create your own Buddha
paradise ok your own and he says it's to
overcome an obstacle and the obstacle is
not having a big enough vision ok the
obstacle is not having a big enough
vision you know I don't know David stump
and I we've been trying to I don't know
if you remember it's been about 7 years
we are trying to remove one big rock
from the road we drilled a hole in there
we put special stuff in and they're
still there
and still you know breaking oil pans and
stuff and so him and me
we were focusing on this one big rock on
the road couldn't dig it out and doctor
rule came he said well let's just take
all the roads you know and we're like an
idea and he says then people can get to
the hotel we're going to build here and
were like you know you said you should
have rooms right here
people shouldn't shouldn't go have an
orange juice and a green drink they
should go back to the room relax on
their bed you know have a delivered a
green drink and then come back to class
you know this is not a good arrangement
you can't get back to your room right
you need
car he said that you should put some not
a hotel but some we call guests with you
know so I don't know I like to I like to
hangout him because his vision is so big
you know right we built a little college
in Sudan he says yeah that's just the
beginning of the university right
there's going to be a thousand students
there I said well okay and that'll be
one of the ones that we build in Germany
and Mexico and China right I'm like yeah
so this section is supposed to be about
don't make your vision too small in
tibetan is called make patchouli light
Shep a Goomba in your meditation
don't make your vision too small and the
Buddha says okay the Congress spoke once
more suppose dosa booty that a
bodhisattva were to say I am working to
bring about my paradise okay I am
working to bring about my paradise
then Buddha says that Bodhisattva is a
liar okay he says very hard thing is you
know
suppose somebody stopper has a big
vision and they're going to build their
own Buddha paradise we call build your
paradise right in Buddhism you have to
build it you can't just go there okay
you have to build it like diamond if you
can't build guest suites at Diamond
Mountain and put in a road how are you
going to build a Buddha paradise
this is just a little one okay then he
says and anybody supper who said he's
going to build a paradise that
Bodhisattva is a liar okay all right
and that's because the that be careful
about looking ahead into the future at
the diamond mountain you want to be here
in five years right or the the
university you want to build in Berlin's
River you know and when you're looking
ahead to that dream you have don't think
of it as something that happens it's
something the growth okay
things don't happen they grow out of
seeds that you plant okay and and in the
beginning at Diamond Mountain we had a
nice policy which I think Susan started
me
instituted as a board member every month
we gave away some of our income to a
competing retreat center it was very
hard you know we were talking about
fundraising we were I had like 20 ideas
then she's like can I say something and
I'm like all right and she's like maybe
we could just give some of our income to
a a retreat center that competes with us
and everybody's like you know maybe
that's a good idea then I remembered at
that time we had a debt for this
property we had a big debt and we went
to the bank on so confident Inc and we
paid it we paid the debt for this whole
land there's no mortgage on this one and
the bank people are like wow you're 30
years early you know every like yeah
yeah this is how much you charge your
programs nothing how do you make money
duh you know we give away our money to
competing dumbest in a second
all right I don't think we follow that
policy got struggling right now so
meanings oh we do okay all right so you
have to understand that a Buddha
paradise which died mountain is halfway
there
it's coming from seats in your mind okay
helping others to get to their Buddha
Turner okay then
Camila Sheila refers to say like to my
sternum doom Said's la chun-li sinem did
didn't mean 7/10 and there are seven how
you saying don't win there gg7
kinds of karma that are called
you call it compounding interest karma
compound means you get interest and you
get interest on the interest and you get
interest on the interest on the interest
name okay it keeps going like that and
there are seven kinds that are special
commerce for Lee cooks make special
commerce for making your Buddha paradise
seven okay first one it's called khumba
Rama which means build retreat cottages
and gardens for other people to use okay
some people do these things by instinct
and that's the first one clean gorilla
second one super calm anybody know at
silicon silicon is the ancient word for
temple so build temples for people to
have classicism so far mr. Dunn and
David's company started me and all these
other people have two of them
the idea is 20 years later
if someone's using that temple you'll
get more karma on top of your old comer
okay every time someone uses that
retreat cottage you get more karma even
if you're even if you move to Australia
okay it doesn't matter the Karma follows
you
every time someone stays in your retreat
cottage you'll get more Karma for your
practice okay got it
number three Melton Melton means
furnishing the retreat College
especially with mattresses and bedding
okay Tahir understand so some people
have instincts she bought all your
bedding by the way got done already okay
yes number four so a normal toilet
normal means cook continuously for
retreatants and people you know
attending these programs so what normal
means okay excuse me but it's the shape
of when your nose is running and you get
this long it means you keep feeding
people feeding him okay nama it's also a
stage in the room but anyway so enormous
low bird 300 serving guests who show up
at your retreat center especially those
who don't give you enough warning ahead
of
it's called Lewbert Lewbert
guess who show up especially without
they're not prepared and they didn't let
you know they're coming we have like
five of those in HCI they're permanent
it's a permanent ACI position every year
they come late I mean they register they
don't register this short okay if your
word and you're interested in these
things lubbers the name of the
adventitious dumber body which you
create see it happens suddenly as
opposed to the kind that's always been
there created rather than pre-existing
okay anyway number what six serving
people and retreat who are not well who
have lung problem they have medical
problems we had someone in Thailand fell
off the trolley right Jasmine forced
everybody to get insurance and then we
were so happy
someone cut their head they said they
stepped off the the bus and they fell
down and okay so she got that kind of
good karma okay
we're also very lucky at this program
there's a doctor here he was trained as
a surgeon he used to cut people's hearts
open and stuff and then after that he
trained as a anesthesiologist put you to
sleep before operation which is a very
dangerous position you can kill people
and then he got interested in ACI
courses many years ago in New York
studied with myeloma and then he sent
out correspondence course before
internet we used to send papers hundred
thousands of papers out to people who
took ACR courses
so he and his wife did all of doors and
especially to prisons all along the
world
so you have to have special papers to
send to prisons because they don't want
anything they can use to make a knife or
something like that so he took out many
many hundreds of prisoners give them
free ACI courses and then for many years
I think 30 years every time Dahmer
person gets sick they just call him he
checks them and he gives them medicine
without payment ok
understand pretty cool Karma and he's
here today and it's Michael Moore
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you for coming I heard it the
first week he gives anesthesiology to
prisoners who can't dental have money so
he does it for free in prison and this
is the first week he had off in seven
years okay thank you for coming all
right
we are lucky number seven
helping people who are particularly poor
particularly having emergency like our
New York Center three jewels now works
with the city of New York to teach
meditation and yoga to homeless people
and that's the southern sky people
really don't have any money in our no
support okay all right those are seven
specific commas to get your Buddha
paradise okay if you understand where
it's coming from you know you cannot go
there in a long march Chinese rocket
it's not somewhere past the moon okay
Kushina paradise is here right you're
making enough good karma it will be here
okay you don't get there by getting on
an airplane a special rocket okay you
make it with those seven kinds of karma
for example then Buddhist then Carmela
Sheila says why did Buddha say Chitra
view harm say chakra view hard
ketamine's theorem but it means buddha
paradise okay perfume you guys are gonna
be my Sutra means to put it together to
put together your Buddha Paris okay
it's like putting together a vacation to
Hawaii right I'm Tom gratitude yes you
have to get the money ready you have to
go online find a nice hotel make sure
there's a good surf there and arranged
to rent a surfboard and you know have
someone take care of your car and that's
called view huh
so he rejected you huh means set up your
vacation to your Buddha tonight okay
view huh but you home is plural so
common lishchyna says why did Buddha say
Buddha paradise is okay yeah each one
makes their own in the same place okay
each one makes their own paradise in the
same place some people say like Tahir
told me get LA this is the most
beautiful piece of land in the whole
United States you know and then other
people try to make Islam this is the
luckiest piece of land in the whole
United States you know and they're both
true ok depends on your scene right okay
so coming to Sheila says each one of us
will make our own bird of paradise okay
and that's why brother said plural denny
again just going deep and i don't care
about the time but i'm not going to go
that long okay don't don't don't worry
say my dog much cheaper
my dark magic are very famous Mario
maker word methought Makeba means if you
don't look too closely everything's fine
okay if you don't look too closely the
world is okay you know you start looking
closely you realize like if you say how
can the seed for that tree cause the
tree if the seed never exists at the
same times the tree how can the seed
affect the tree right then you look too
close then the tree is impossible okay
so my time I different means
you know don't become dysfunctional
don't go around the world like oh well
that Green Drinks not possible yeah not
always just noise you can possibly you
know but you have to deal with the world
you know my dad my tipper it's okay
there's orange juice drinking okay
don't like get weird don't get a weird
Buddhist okay there are weird Buddhist
tree
everything's okay Buddha paradise is
Buddha paradise you will go there it's
it will be there but at the same time
remember you are making it like the
diamond cutter Sutra you created the
Sutra and you create your Buddha
paradise okay that's your job it seems
to me like a good way to create your
Buddha paradise is to volunteer at
Diamond Mountain because like six of
those things are here all the time you
know seems to me it would be a really
efficient way to put together your
Buddha paradise
okay beYOU huh but
how you talk about the Paradise okay how
you talk about your paradise if you say
I'm gonna go to kishida heaven because
my llama bless me or something like that
okay I'm gonna go to Takeda hummus all
right you already a liar because what
you when you say heaven
you think it's already there okay you
think you know it was there a long time
ago some Buddha probably worked really
hard built it and then you get to go
there if you're a nice person
okay when you say I'm gonna go to she to
paradise
I went to do a metaphor mantra and Joe
and I will go to I'm Adolfo's heaven
already you made a mistake already
you're a liar okay there's no such thing
there is no amituofo heaven okay there's
no there you can go to you have to make
it okay the part of a McDonald's heaven
that you go to you have to make it
okay got it and if you if you use the
word amitabha's paradise in the wrong
way you're a liar
because because that word has no meaning
there's no such thing
okay got it that's why Buddha said if
someone said I'm gonna make my paradise
then they do not speak the truth he said
okay got it
just nod all right then Buddha says
remember don't stay in colors don't stay
in shape don't stay in sounds don't stay
and smells don't stay and tastes don't
stay in touches and don't stay in
thoughts but he already said that part
it's a repetition then combinations is
why does bitter repeated and in this
case he says some people already forgot
okay during the teaching bye
this time some people forgot Cumberland
number one right so Buddha said it again
okay so don't think he's crazy he has to
say it again want to go deeper you have
time you don't have an appointment with
with a wild pig which of the three
questions relates to this question to
this part you tell me
she says number three yeah it's a
distraction it's talking about the third
question of sebou tea how am I supposed
to think how am I supposed to focus and
Buddha says focus when you're talking
about diamond cutter Sutra means you
don't think your husband come from his
own side that's destruction got it okay
you want to go deeper okay
he says there's two kinds of destruction
don't talk and couldn't say John don't
condemn very famous in mind only school
for example don't dog means you believe
something is there which is not there
you believe something is there which is
not there in the case of the husband the
husband who's not my fault is not there
but you believe it is there so we say
over estimate over rape there's nothing
there but you make something then it's
called over overestimate two months
there there is no husband there who's
not your song but you create one and
that's our most common mistake okay we
make people there who hurt us and we
don't understand they come from us we
create them where there's nothing okay
but Camila Sheila says in this case you
during the opposite what's that mean
your your distraction is the opposite
current something's there that you could
have that you you think you couldn't
make something's there that you could
make but you think you can't one guest
suites at diamond pave all the roads at
Diamond month make three universities
around the world for people to go to or
make your paradise so he says in this
case that distraction is underrating
underestimate your capacity occasional I
can't even make a new toilet in my
retreat cottage how am I gonna build a
Buddha paradise you know okay like I
can't figure out the refrigerator how am
I gonna build a Buddha paradise I
figured it out yesterday but it took a
you know a while okay we were so happy
okay huh so don't underrate yourself you
are a paradise maker you are Buddha give
birth or to your your special person you
can give birth to Buddha's and you can
create paradises don't underrate
yourself that's a kind of breaking Cebu
T third question you are distracted
under underestimate yourself
okay got it cool alright then he goes on
in the future he goes on to hey how
about the people gonna stand my paradise
with me okay who's gonna make them me
okay that's easy I'm not going to teach
you that okay he mentions somebody with
a big body okay he says you're gonna
have people in your credits with a big
body and Camila Sheila says that's
Rahula rahula is
like this berry God who's as big as a
planet their bodies has because they use
planets like marbles they play games
with planets you know fun like do I got
three okay that's me okay they play with
planets okay big guy
but even that body is coming from you
okay even big one okay and that's okay
I'll go very fast to a very complicated
thing and that's because they're their
body of the people you make and your
paradise are neither one nor many they
are not whole and they are not parts
okay do they have part yes they have
arms legs head okay the people you're
going to live within your paradise like
your mom and your dad they're you're
gonna meet them again they're gonna be
in your paradise okay for sure okay then
are they one thing or are they many
things are they many pieces or are they
one thing neither one neither one
okay is it one thing or two piece or two
pieces then in Buddhism we say neither
one why two pieces aren't there by
themselves that also coming from me when
I put it together
it becomes one thing that also coming
from me how many pins which are pieces
coming this way none how many pens which
are one thing coming this way none
therefore nothing is one of many okay
got it
and therefore everything is one or many
no problem mayo and tea okay let's go
we're almost done that's so easy
we'll get we're getting there what's
going on is there anymore
oh my gosh yikes I'm gonna try not to
rush okay I'll try to relax
you too you too okay I'll give you one
more PP break don't worry meditation
number 24 karma stupas journeys on
teachers
so the one of the biggest things in the
ancient India was the Ganges River and
if you ever I don't know if you go from
Varanasi to west and Gulf been gone you
have to cross some places the the bridge
is like a mile long
the Ganges is big okay then Buddha said
soluti try to imagine all the jobs of
water in the Ganges River okay got it
then he said imagine that each of those
drops of water becomes another Ganges
River
okay Ganges River is equal in number to
the jobs in this country of rivers okay
and then suppose each one of those jobs
is its own planet is a separate planet
and then suppose somebody covered those
with diamonds or gold and offer them to
the Buddhist okay would that be a good
karma would you get a lot of good karma
and then of course the Buddha says yes
and then Buddha says if you teach one
verse of this future to another person
it's more good karma okay all right
it's more good karma then then Buddha
starts going crazy and saying all the
good karma you're going to get if you
teach this Sutra okay and Matthew koma
Sheela summarizes it in four different
kinds of karma okay ready
so this is meditation twenty-four I put
four words up there Carmel stupas
journeys teachers okay these are the
four things that are going to happen if
you teach the diamond cutter in New York
or Singapore or
guangzhou or wherever you are okay here
we go number one you make a huge good
kamma okay we talked about it if you
interested in the sutra the words are
they would indeed create much merit cebu
t says they would indeed create much
merit okay that's indicating the first
of the four results of teaching the
diamond kana you get our there's an
english word which I can't say
especially with via something load of
karma okay
secondly that place where you taught it
becomes a stupa it means that becomes a
holy place I was teaching the diamond
cutter Sutra in a small hotel room there
was no place to sit we were sitting on
the bed everybody was sitting on the bed
and if it's if people in this world
really understood how important it is to
talk about these ideas then that bed in
room 3 6 4 aim would become a holy place
and people would come there just to walk
around the bed all day and do mantras no
I was thinking we have to push the bed
into the middle of the room so there's
enough room to just enough room to walk
around ok then you laugh but it's true
you know people go to these temples and
maybe nothing ever happened there you
know it's just biggest one people like I
built the biggest temple I have the
biggest Buddha I went to see the biggest
Buddha forget it you know if you teach
King ganjam correctly he said correctly
right in a in a shim Baca in a Starbucks
in Guangzhou then later generation
should walk around that Starbucks to get
good karma
because that became holy place because
something really important happened
there not there's a sub coot of Buddha
that's maybe a tooth of a dog we don't
know you know forget it or it's the
biggest Buddha in Asia forgetting that
Starbucks become more holy okay that
becomes real stupid okay so I like it
everyone's gonna be walking around sir
my Starbucks can get more business
American economy go up okay by the way
in the Sutra the words are that place
becomes a stupa so those are the direct
words in the center third one journeys
that are difficult to make are made
easily okay journeys spiritual journeys
ok spiritual trips spiritual tasks
become easy become easy things that were
difficult to do become easy ok
and the suture word for that is they
become someone truly wondrous those
people who teach it those people who
study it become special people and karma
Sheila says that means those people can
make their spiritual trip easily
something very difficult long journey to
Buddhahood for them becomes easy ok
that's a third one journey easy journey
fourth one very cool ok
anytime anybody in this room or
listening online teaches diamond cutter
Sutra one sentence to another person
then the Buddha is there ok then the
Buddha is there in the Starbucks then
you say you mean in mind the Buddha you
have to think about it
Buddha's been that big Camilla Sheila
says we're we're in the center did
Buddha say that you want to hear quote
from the Sutra this is because we can
say that the teacher himself is in that
place as well as every other spiritual
teacher who ever lived is in the same
Starbucks at that moment every Lama
every guru every teacher in history is
also in the same stuff but it's really
crowded in this image guangzhou
Starbucks we need this time we gotta see
that they all come they all want to see
you do it it's so cool who said that
Buddha singers not coming here okay good
listener then calmly Sheila says by the
way the reason the Lord Buddha talks
about drops of water in a big river or
ocean and talks about diamonds and gold
is that teaching the diamond cutter is
like water for the planet it's like
ocean for the planet it's like jewels
for the planet it's most precious and
it's everywhere like water
you know emptiness is everywhere like
ocean water and it's precious like
jewels okay so he there's a reason why
he he used the image of jewels and water
what is most precious thing on this
world can't live without water
then in in this section the buddha is
called two other names one is katate the
person who went that way to target on
the person who went that way
and he's also called our hearts ultimate
are hunts and he's also called the
totally enlightened one three names they
give him three other news to target uh
the one who went that way
our hot enemy discern and that totally
enlightened one some young some budaya
some young some Bruner told me
enlightened one okay then calmly Sheila
says that also has meaning gone that way
why is Buddhist called gone that way
Tata gutta okay went that way he says
that way has two meanings that way
meaning number one he took care of other
people's needs and he took care of his
own needs both katha
that's how he made his journey he took
care of what other people needed and he
took her what he needed to talk that
that's how he did it that that was his
style con still o Ultimo alright and
verse also means emptiness of course to
talk that that way means emptiness okay
doc Champa our heart means destroyed
negative parts of himself destroyed them
okay
so Lee enlightened Buddha means got all
the good qualities
he's complete okay so those three names
are added here alright we finished
meditation number twenty-four we're
still going
this one's pretty easy I mean we can do
it pretty quick okay
number 25 what's the picture it's a guy
is he like bored or is he excited he's
excited yeah
he's excited okay because the Sutra here
starts talking about again about
teaching okay
and Buddha says you should explain the
diamond color to other people and you
should teach it correctly okay and then
Kamala Sheila says what's he mean why
does he divide it like that explain me
is to explain the words of the Sutra
okay like we just did guitar guitar we
just did our heart we just did some
yuxun Buddha explain the pieces of the
words that's easy
see teacher correctly means get the
student excited teacher correctly means
get the student excited okay if the
student is bored you're not correcting
you're teaching it but not correctly
well guess very interesting he doesn't
say you have to explain emptiness
correctly he says if you don't inspire
your student you're not teaching it
correctly to inspire your student you
must be a good example okay you must be
a living example she would premiere you
should be right you should be a living
example okay they could look at you and
say Harry Met Sally right should I tell
bad story his family's like yeah
it's excuse me okay I didn't make this
movie it was made by somebody else I
mean there's a movie called Harry Met
Sally in America old movie and it's a
guy and his girlfriend and I didn't see
the movie I just saw him one small part
then they go to a restaurant you know
and Harry says the salad so you know
tell me the truth you know I'm like the
best lover you ever had right when I
make love
nobody could do it like me right and she
looks at him and she says not really and
he gets angry what do you mean she says
you're not really so great you know in
the band you know you just kind of like
average you know then he says not really
great she said no no he says every time
you make love you're like I must be
great you know
she said you never heard a woman comes
take it you're not faking it's real
signal sometimes I have to fake it you
know he says I don't believe it
she says I can fake it right here right
now he says no no she said you want to
see me yeah you try she then she starts
going good everybody in the restaurant
think when did you go he's like
everybody the rest is like this you know
huh what's going on and then this old
lady comes in very well-dressed she has
pearls expensive suit business suit
older lady she comes in she sits down
she's like also watching this video
the waiter comes over and he said
what would you like to have for lunch
you know
and she says give me whatever she's
having
I'll take the same thing why I said that
living he's excited the old lady's
excited I object I don't know what you
doubting but I wanted you know so when
you teach it should be like that okay
like it shouldn't be boring you know it
should be oh come with users and then
you know everybody should be everyone
look at you in 10 I want that you know
what she has I want that you know I told
you many times I went to a meditation
class to check my student debt teaching
good or not you know I sat in the back I
didn't say anything
most people don't know who I am you know
then she's like very nervous person all
the time and she she was teaching
meditation then she got some cup of
coffee and she's like this and you must
be calm in the meditation Dana I was
sitting next to two ladies and one of
them the other one you know I don't know
what kind of meditation she's teaching
but I don't want to learn it that that
meditation I don't want to learn what
she's teaching I don't want to learn
okay
so Buddha said teach correctly means
teach after you experienced it and you
reached it didn't teach it you know
don't be like I don't want to learn what
she's learning that's the opposite of
the lady in the restaurant okay that's
like the lady in the restaurant says
give me anything except what she's
having
okay got it okay just one more point
there there's a word in Heart Sutra
and called checking them down your teens
in Britta goes into meditation at the
beginning of the Heart Sutra he doesn't
say the Heart Sutra it's a discussion
between two students he's in meditation
but that meditation has a word called
Dharma Dharma hallelujah
say Dharma by the ayah and I always
wondered about this word pariah
it means usually that word means synonym
like our heart enemy destroyer deserving
one these are all synonyms they all mean
the same thing okay so for many years I
wondered about what this word means
and it comes in the diamond cutter Sutra
he says anyone who teaches Dharma pariah
diamond cutter okay anyone who teaches
this particular presentation so I
learned to translate it as this
particular presentation of emptiness
called
diamond cutter okay this particular
presentation is called Polya okay then
he explains it come unless she explains
it so if you're interested it also comes
in the heart sutra it's a weird word in
the heart center he says it means this
presentation of emptiness as opposed to
rather than wrong ones okay
rather than wrong ones okay that's all
Buddha keeps saying anyone who teaches
this particular presentation of
emptiness okay this whole section
relates to what Kamla Sheela calls not
getting into wrong teachings and he uses
the word cheap it sounds good it's buck
here outside teachings outside teachings
so if you if you don't know Buddhism
very well
you can say master common our sealants
are saying don't don't study Jewish
teachings don't study Christian those
are outside okay but what's it really
mean yeah wrong teaching about emptiness
is outside teachings don't don't go to
outside teachings and then carmella
Sheila says he's not talking about Hindu
Christian Jewish Muslim he's not talking
about outside like that he's talking
about Buddhist who teach anything is
wrong that's outside don't go to outside
going just not I know your time I don't
care I think we got two more to go I'm
sorry okay what's the next picture
sailing ship okay sailing ship ship for
old ship sailing okay would be sail for
the wind now this is a cool part in the
Sutra the Buddha says to Lord Buddha I
like this Sutra you're teaching today I
really like it what's the name of the
suture you know later when we talk about
it what's the name of the Sutra the
Buddha doesn't say diamond cleansing
okay no we're in this sutras does Buddha
say diamond color diamonds aren't
mentioned in this Sutra only the title
is diamond cutter okay and the title is
exquisite that title is the best title
you could give to any book okay it's
exactly correct and if you don't know
about it by the diamond cutter business
book and it's in the first few chapters
okay diamond is important cutting the
diamond is more important okay anyone
who calls the diamond cutter Sutra the
Diamond Sutra
doesn't get it at all nothing
throw it out if you see that books throw
it out okay anyone who calls a diamond
cutter to to Diamond Sutra doesn't
understand anything about the Sutra okay
don't even open it okay sorry but that's
how I really think okay so what does
Buddha say I think you should call this
book bolo bolo middle but not bottom
Itza okay you should call it the
perfection of wisdom that's all
sometimes it's called the
professionalism in seven hundred lines
acting okay he says call it the
perfection of wisdom and then comma
Sheela starts to explain the word Raja
parameter okay
Raja L parameter perfection of wisdom in
Chinese buh-buh-buh amido right put a
bottom middle okay same word bara means
the other side para means the other son
other son yeah
it demeans gone and it exists in English
in the word exit X means out it means
gone go out X it means go out okay this
is a place to go out so it and then M on
the bottom means the object of this verb
so go across go to the other side ba ba
la mota parameter sorry just kidding
bottom it bottom it long a bottom yeah
so it means gone to the other side but
as Joanie Lama points out it's really
harder to chamber politic in jake
peralta change a parameter maker it's
not gone to the other side
it gets you to the other side the other
side of this ocean pacific ocean is
guangzhou area shenzhen Hong Kong okay
that's bottom compared to San Francisco
in Los Angeles
okay but you haven't gone there you're
going down okay
this Citra takes you there this is not
guangzhou it's the ship
okay got in so the worm it is gone
already to the other side but it means
the ship that takes you to the other
side it's not the other Sun got it okay
the word is a misnomer the word is a not
correct it's not a perfection it's a
perfection Iser okay it makes you
perfect it's not a perfection okay we
are not studying the perfection of
wisdom we are studying wisdom which
makes you perfect okay it's not a
perfection yet okay so the word is
mistaken where the ship is the
perfection it was and now ask you a
question is the book of perfection
wisdom
no the idea is professionalism
understand Kong Ching understand your
husband takes you to the other side
understand he's not there the one who's
not your fault is not there that takes
you to the other side if the book
teaches you that we can give the book
that name but it's just a name it's not
the book is not the idea many people
have the book and they still fight with
your husband right it means it didn't
take them to the other side okay they
have the perfection of wisdom in their
house they pray to it every morning they
read it every morning and then they get
up and fight with their husband then it
that wasn't a professional okay
got in okay all right
other kinds of knowledge are that are
not dis because they cannot take you to
the other side of the ocean of pain
that's camera Sheila other kinds of
understanding are not progeny parameter
because they cannot take you to the
other side of the ocean of pain so the
ocean is pain ocean is trouble with your
husband okay
ocean is trouble if you have this idea
you can cross it if you don't have this
idea nothing else can help you you can
go to a marriage counselor they all tell
you stuff you know stop squeezing the
toothpaste from the left side squeeze it
from the bottom your husband will be
happier you know no people say stuff
like that but it doesn't fix it forever
okay all right I'm going to read you one
more thing and I'm going to stop for
today because I think you're getting
tired and we'll just have to do a longer
one at different days there's a
beautiful prayer time in Tantra Biagio
Guinea jungle Jammu and there's a famous
prayer called gotcha shelf song tower
moon mom it's the prayer to see her
beautiful face okay it's called the
prayer to see her beautiful face her
beautiful smiling face of the woman of
the sky okay which is vagi eginning
highest buddha is possessive woman okay
don't tell other men
okay and it's a prayer to see her say so
many of you studied here at Diamond
Mountain Tundra you know this prayer and
it's secret but there's a part in it
from the Lamia so I'm going to read it
to you because it's then you can
understand the ship Rani
okay this is just for good luck those
people who come to Lamia regularly I
will teach Tantra later those who don't
I will not clear all right you don't
have to come every time because then
you'll be bankrupt and your husband will
leave you but I try to come you know
pretty frequently okay
all right not not going don't be crazy
but just when you can okay okay
I pray that by the power of the good
karma of studying this diamond cutter
okay this is the prayer I may be taken
under the care of a lama who possesses
every qualification because these are
the real source of every spiritual goal
may I always please my lover and never
be apart from him or her and by the
power of this deed may I board the good
ship on spiritual leisure unfortunately
may I set the white sails of constantly
remembering my death and that wind will
make the ship go okay remembering my
death and then on the trip I should have
the fair winds of carefully observing
the laws of karma and its consequences
what you will learn in Guadalajara and
you already learned in DC is and may
that wind carry my ship across the
terror of the sea of the cycle of pain
that we live in now okay that's prayer
very famous ship okay